<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Netsparse · Angel Nevarez</title>
    <link>https://netsparse.dev/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Netsparse · Angel Nevarez</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 06 Apr 2023 16:35:08 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://netsparse.dev/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Automate Your Infrastructure With Ansible</title>
      <link>https://netsparse.dev/posts/2023-04/automate-your-infrastructure-with-ansible/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Apr 2023 16:35:08 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://netsparse.dev/posts/2023-04/automate-your-infrastructure-with-ansible/</guid>
      <description>Automating your infrastructure with Ansible can be a game-changer for any organization looking to streamline their processes and reduce manual labor.
Ansible is an open-source automation tool that allows you to automate tasks such as configuration management, application deployment, and orchestration of infrastructure resources, using a declarative language to describe the desired state of a system.
One of the key benefits of Ansible is its simplicity and ease of use.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build a Quick Website With Hugo</title>
      <link>https://netsparse.dev/posts/2023-04/build-a-quick-website-with-hugo/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Apr 2023 21:25:31 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://netsparse.dev/posts/2023-04/build-a-quick-website-with-hugo/</guid>
      <description>Hugo is a popular static site generator written in Go. It allows you to create and manage static websites quickly and easily.
In this guide, we will cover the basics of getting started with Hugo.
Here&amp;rsquo;s a quick overview from Fireship.io.
Get Started Installation Download the appropriate package for your system.
Windows Mac OS Linux Content Management Creating a New Site 1 hugo new site &amp;lt;your-site-name&amp;gt; This will create a new Hugo site in a directory named mysite.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Migrating My Site From Jekyll to Hugo</title>
      <link>https://netsparse.dev/posts/2023-04/how-i-migrated-my-site/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Apr 2023 13:03:23 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://netsparse.dev/posts/2023-04/how-i-migrated-my-site/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been utilizing Jekyll for the past few months to build my website. Although it does a pretty good job at doing so, I&amp;rsquo;ve been taking a look at Hugo and experimenting alongside it.
I was able to replicate my website on Hugo with a better looking theme and decided to take the leap. I went ahead and migrated my posts and basic items, making sure everything was nicely organized. And so far, it works pretty good!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Seamless File Sync Solution With Syncthing</title>
      <link>https://netsparse.dev/posts/2023-03/seamless-file-sync/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Mar 2023 18:11:16 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://netsparse.dev/posts/2023-03/seamless-file-sync/</guid>
      <description>Syncthing is a free, open-source file synchronization software that enables you to synchronize files between your devices securely.
Unlike traditional cloud-based storage solutions, Syncthing is decentralized, meaning it uses peer-to-peer technology which allow you to sync files between devices without the need for traditional cloud-based storage solutions or SMB/NFS systems.
In this article, we will explore how to get started with Syncthing and utilize it to sync some files with our devices.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quick Data Backup Guide</title>
      <link>https://netsparse.dev/posts/2023-03/data-backup-guide/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Mar 2023 14:00:38 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://netsparse.dev/posts/2023-03/data-backup-guide/</guid>
      <description>Data is arguably one of the most important assets in our modern world. We use computers, smartphones, and other devices to store and access our personal and professional information.
However, these devices are not immune to failures or accidents. In the event of a hard drive crash, theft, or other catastrophic event, having a backup of your data is critical.
In this post, we will discuss the importance of backups, the 3-2-1 method, and how to backup your Linux, Windows, and Mac machines so that you can rest assured that your data is safe.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quick Intro To Powershell</title>
      <link>https://netsparse.dev/posts/2023-03/quick-powershell-scripting/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Mar 2023 23:41:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://netsparse.dev/posts/2023-03/quick-powershell-scripting/</guid>
      <description>PowerShell is a command-line scripting language developed by Microsoft that is designed to automate administrative tasks and manage system configurations. It provides a powerful framework for managing Windows-based systems and automating repetitive tasks.
Scripts are written in the PowerShell scripting language, which is based on the .NET framework.
The language includes features such as variables, loops, conditionals, and functions, which allow you to write scripts to perform a wide range of tasks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quick Intro To Bash Scripting</title>
      <link>https://netsparse.dev/posts/2023-03/quick-bash-scripting/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Mar 2023 20:46:08 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://netsparse.dev/posts/2023-03/quick-bash-scripting/</guid>
      <description>Bash scripting is a powerful tool that enables users to automate tasks and streamline workflows in Unix-based operating systems, such as Linux and macOS.
It can be used for a variety of purposes, including system administration, web development, data analysis, and more.
Here&amp;rsquo;s a quick overview from Fireship.io.
Components Commands Consist of a series of commands that are executed one after the other.
These commands can be standard Linux commands or custom commands written specifically for the script.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting Started With Git</title>
      <link>https://netsparse.dev/posts/2023-03/getting-started-with-git/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Mar 2023 23:32:13 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://netsparse.dev/posts/2023-03/getting-started-with-git/</guid>
      <description>Git is a powerful and widely used version control system that allows developers to manage changes to their codebase efficiently.
Whether you are working on a solo project or collaborating with a team, Git provides a simple and effective way to keep track of changes and revert to previous versions if necessary.
In this article, we will cover the basics of using Git, including creating a repository, making changes, committing those changes, and pushing them to a remote repository.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hands-on with Python</title>
      <link>https://netsparse.dev/posts/2023-03/hands-on-python/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Mar 2023 22:50:11 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://netsparse.dev/posts/2023-03/hands-on-python/</guid>
      <description>Python is a high-level, interpreted programming language that is widely used for web development, data analysis, artificial intelligence, and other applications.
It has a clean syntax and is easy to learn, making it a great choice for beginners as well as experienced developers.
Here&amp;rsquo;s a quick overview from Fireship.io.
Overview Variables and Data Types In Python, variables are used to store values such as numbers, strings, and other data types.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Setup WireGuard VPN Server with Ubiquiti Edgerouter X (EdgeOS)</title>
      <link>https://netsparse.dev/posts/2023-03/setup-wireguard-edgerouter/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://netsparse.dev/posts/2023-03/setup-wireguard-edgerouter/</guid>
      <description>WireGuard is a fast and secure VPN protocol that uses state-of-the-art cryptography. It is designed to be easy to implement and manage, and has a minimal attack surface. Its simplicity and efficiency make it well-suited for use in mobile devices and large-scale deployments.
Note: Before making any major changes on your EdgeOS router, always make a backup. Refer to the official documentation on how to perform one.
Breakdown Step 1. Installation Note: The following installation guide was verified working on EdgeOS v2.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Take Your Ad Blocking With You On The Go With NextDNS</title>
      <link>https://netsparse.dev/posts/2023-03/take-your-ad-blocking-with-you-with-nextdns/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Mar 2023 22:48:26 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://netsparse.dev/posts/2023-03/take-your-ad-blocking-with-you-with-nextdns/</guid>
      <description>In our previous post, we setup a Pi-hole DNS server to block ads on our local network.
Although the Pi-hole is awesome, unfortunately it only works on our local network, and thus we don&amp;rsquo;t get the same benefits of ad blocking when we leaving the network.
Today, I&amp;rsquo;ll show you how you can setup NextDNS on your mobile or laptop devices for whenever you need ad blocking on the go.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Block Ads for All Your Devices with Pi-Hole DNS and Docker</title>
      <link>https://netsparse.dev/posts/2023-03/pihole-dns-with-docker/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Mar 2023 23:32:47 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://netsparse.dev/posts/2023-03/pihole-dns-with-docker/</guid>
      <description>Pi-hole is a DNS sinkhole that blocks advertisements, trackers, and other unwanted content from being served to devices on your network.
It can be run on a Raspberry Pi or other hardware, but running it in a Docker container has some benefits, such as easier installation and management.
If you are also new to Docker, check out my previous post on how to get started with Docker.
A Bit of History The Pi-hole project was started by Jacob Salmela in 2014 as an open source alternative to AdTrap, which was a device that would block advertisements and tracking domains at the network level.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Awesome Diagrams and Graphs for Your Documentation</title>
      <link>https://netsparse.dev/posts/2023-02/create-awesome-diagrams-and-graphs-for-your-docs/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Feb 2023 17:05:15 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://netsparse.dev/posts/2023-02/create-awesome-diagrams-and-graphs-for-your-docs/</guid>
      <description>Diagrams.net (or Draw.io) is a free and open source cross-platform graph drawing software developed in HTML5 and JavaScript by UK-based JGraph Ltd in 2000.
Its interface can be used to create diagrams such as flowcharts, network diagrams, organizational charts, or any other type of diagram.
It is a useful alternative to more commercial tools like Microsoft Visio or Lucidchart.
Getting Started You can immediately start by heading over to the web application at app.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Create Awesome Notes With Obsidian</title>
      <link>https://netsparse.dev/posts/2023-02/awesome-notes-with-obsidian/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Feb 2023 17:03:06 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://netsparse.dev/posts/2023-02/awesome-notes-with-obsidian/</guid>
      <description>Obsidian is a powerful note-taking tool that allows you to create, organize, and link your notes in a way that makes sense to you. It&amp;rsquo;s a flexible and customizable tool that can be used for a variety of purposes, from personal journaling to project management.
Getting Started Obsidian is available for Windows, Mac OS, Linux, Android, and iOS. Download the installer and install it on your system.
Create A Vault To create a new empty vault from the vault switcher:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Manage Your Docker Environment With Portainer</title>
      <link>https://netsparse.dev/posts/2023-02/manage-your-docker-env-with-portainer/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Feb 2023 18:25:12 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://netsparse.dev/posts/2023-02/manage-your-docker-env-with-portainer/</guid>
      <description>Portainer is a simple and open-source web application for managing Docker containers. It lets users easily deploy and manage Docker-based applications through a web interface, without needing to use the command-line tools.
It supports various Docker environments and provides role-based access control, making it suitable for both individuals and organizations. Portainer is also highly extensible, allowing users to add more functionalities and integrate with other tools and platforms.
Deployment Install Portainer Community Edition (CE) First, create the volume that Portainer Server will use to store its database:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Running Docker containers in a Proxmox LXC container</title>
      <link>https://netsparse.dev/posts/2023-02/docker-on-lxc/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://netsparse.dev/posts/2023-02/docker-on-lxc/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;One awesome feature in Proxmox VE is to run an LXC (Linux Container) directly from the web interface.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Get Started with Docker</title>
      <link>https://netsparse.dev/posts/2023-02/get-started-with-docker/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Feb 2023 17:54:59 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://netsparse.dev/posts/2023-02/get-started-with-docker/</guid>
      <description>Docker and Docker Compose are powerful tools that allow you to run and manage applications in containers, making it easy to set up and run applications on any machine, whether it be a laptop, desktop or server.
Here&amp;rsquo;s a quick overview from Fireship.io.
Overview Docker is a platform that enables developers to create, deploy, and run applications in containers.
Containers are lightweight, portable, and self-contained units of software that can run virtually anywhere.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Setup a VM Server with Proxmox VE</title>
      <link>https://netsparse.dev/posts/2023-02/setup-a-vm-server/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Feb 2023 20:49:05 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://netsparse.dev/posts/2023-02/setup-a-vm-server/</guid>
      <description>Proxmox is a powerful, open-source virtualization management platform that allows you to create and manage virtual machines (VMs) and containers on a single server. It is a popular choice for home labbing, where enthusiasts use it to create and test different configurations of operating systems, applications, and network setups.
In this article, I&amp;rsquo;ll guide you through the steps required to set up a Proxmox server for home labbing.
Requirements A 64-bit CPU with Intel VT/AMD-V virtualization support At least 4GB of RAM (8GB or more is recommended) At least 16GB of storage space for the operating system and Proxmox installation At least one Ethernet port for network connectivity Setup Download and Install Proxmox Head over to the Downloads section on Proxmox&amp;rsquo;s site and download the installation ISO.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why a Homelab?</title>
      <link>https://netsparse.dev/posts/2023-02/why-a-homelab/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://netsparse.dev/posts/2023-02/why-a-homelab/</guid>
      <description>A homelab is a place where you can experiment, learn, and grow in ways you never thought possible. You can build yourself an environment to test and tinker with some technologies you may be interested in, practice setting up networks and operating systems, and explore cutting-edge technologies.
With a homelab, you&amp;rsquo;re not just reading about the technology - you&amp;rsquo;re experiencing it firsthand. It&amp;rsquo;s a space where you can make mistakes and learn from them, without the fear of potentially damaging a production environment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2023 Lab Overview</title>
      <link>https://netsparse.dev/posts/2023-01/lab-overview/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://netsparse.dev/posts/2023-01/lab-overview/</guid>
      <description>A general overview of the 2 home labs and networks I have designed, currently manage, and maintain.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Starting This Site</title>
      <link>https://netsparse.dev/posts/2023-01/journey/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Jan 2023 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://netsparse.dev/posts/2023-01/journey/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;So it&amp;rsquo;s been quite the journey figuring out the ins &amp;amp; outs of setting up a blog and writing posts in markdown.
So I figured I may as well write about it.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
