<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>docker-compose on NS</title>
    <link>/tags/docker-compose/</link>
    <description>Recent content in docker-compose on NS</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 16 Feb 2023 18:25:12 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/docker-compose/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Manage Your Docker Environment With Portainer</title>
      <link>/posts/2023-02/manage-your-docker-env-with-portainer/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Feb 2023 18:25:12 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2023-02/manage-your-docker-env-with-portainer/</guid>
      <description>Portainer is a simple and open-source web application for managing Docker containers. It lets users easily deploy and manage Docker-based applications through a web interface, without needing to use the command-line tools.
It supports various Docker environments and provides role-based access control, making it suitable for both individuals and organizations. Portainer is also highly extensible, allowing users to add more functionalities and integrate with other tools and platforms.
Deployment Install Portainer Community Edition (CE) First, create the volume that Portainer Server will use to store its database:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Get Started with Docker</title>
      <link>/posts/2023-02/get-started-with-docker/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Feb 2023 17:54:59 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2023-02/get-started-with-docker/</guid>
      <description>Docker and Docker Compose are powerful tools that allow you to run and manage applications in containers, making it easy to set up and run applications on any machine, whether it be a laptop, desktop or server.
Here&amp;rsquo;s a quick overview from Fireship.io.
   Overview Docker is a platform that enables developers to create, deploy, and run applications in containers.
Containers are lightweight, portable, and self-contained units of software that can run virtually anywhere.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
