<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>app on NS</title>
    <link>/tags/app/</link>
    <description>Recent content in app on NS</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 30 Mar 2023 18:11:16 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/app/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Seamless File Sync Solution With Syncthing</title>
      <link>/posts/2023-03/seamless-file-sync/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Mar 2023 18:11:16 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2023-03/seamless-file-sync/</guid>
      <description>Syncthing is a free, open-source file synchronization software that enables you to synchronize files between your devices securely.
Unlike traditional cloud-based storage solutions, Syncthing is decentralized, meaning it uses peer-to-peer technology which allow you to sync files between devices without the need for traditional cloud-based storage solutions or SMB/NFS systems.
In this article, we will explore how to get started with Syncthing and utilize it to sync some files with our devices.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Awesome Diagrams and Graphs for Your Documentation</title>
      <link>/posts/2023-02/create-awesome-diagrams-and-graphs-for-your-docs/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Feb 2023 17:05:15 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2023-02/create-awesome-diagrams-and-graphs-for-your-docs/</guid>
      <description>Diagrams.net (or Draw.io) is a free and open source cross-platform graph drawing software developed in HTML5 and JavaScript by UK-based JGraph Ltd in 2000.
Its interface can be used to create diagrams such as flowcharts, network diagrams, organizational charts, or any other type of diagram.
It is a useful alternative to more commercial tools like Microsoft Visio or Lucidchart.
Getting Started You can immediately start by heading over to the web application at app.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Create Awesome Notes With Obsidian</title>
      <link>/posts/2023-02/awesome-notes-with-obsidian/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Feb 2023 17:03:06 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2023-02/awesome-notes-with-obsidian/</guid>
      <description>Overview Obsidian is a powerful note-taking tool that allows you to create, organize, and link your notes in a way that makes sense to you. It&amp;rsquo;s a flexible and customizable tool that can be used for a variety of purposes, from personal journaling to project management.
Getting Started Obsidian is available for Windows, Mac OS, Linux, Android, and iOS. Download the installer and install it on your system.
Create A Vault To create a new empty vault from the vault switcher:</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
